My name is Mr. Brown and this is
(تم転사 بواسطة TurboScribe.ai. انتقل إلى Unlimited لإزالة هذه الرسالة.) اسمي الأستاذ براون وهذا
a video for my second grade language class
فيديو لدرس اللغة لصفّي الثاني
during the coronavirus quarantine in Comayagua, Honduras.
خلال فترة عزل كورونا في كوماياغوا، هندوراس.
Hello everybody, I hope all of you are
مرحباً بالجميع، أتمنى أن تكونوا جميعاً
happy and that you are washing your hands.
سعداء وأنكم تغسلون أيديكم.
Today our objective is to spell common verbs
هدفنا اليوم هو تهجئة الأفعال الشائعة
and pronounce them correctly by watching a slideshow
ونطقها بشكل صحيح من خلال مشاهدة عرض الشرائح
and writing the words together.
وكتابة الكلمات معاً.
Does anybody know what a verb is?
هل يعرف أحدكم ما هو الفعل؟
A verb is an action word.
الفعل هو كلمة تدل على عمل أو حركة.
Do you remember when we played Simon Says
هل تتذكرون عندما لعبنا لعبة 'Simon Says'؟ (لعبة الأوامر)
a couple of weeks ago?
قبل بضعة أسابيع؟
Yes?
نعم؟
What are some of the words that you
ما هي بعض الكلمات التي تعلمتموها
learned from Simon Says?
من لعبة 'Simon Says'؟ (لعبة الأوامر)
Here are some that I remember.
إليكم بعض ما أتذكره.
Play, walk, run, eat, jump, stomp, clap,
Play, walk, run, eat, jump, stomp, clap,
drink, read, write, sit, close, open.
drink, read, write, sit, close, open.
Do you know any others?
هل تعرفون كلمات أخرى؟
Do you remember more?
هل تتذكرون المزيد؟
Let's practice together some more.
دعونا نتدرب معاً على المزيد.
I will test you on your pronunciation later.
سأستمع إلى نطقكم لاحقًا.
For this activity, you're going to need a
لهذا النشاط، ستحتاجون إلى قلم رصاص
pencil and a piece of paper.
وقطعة من الورق.
Watch the images and write the word for
شاهدوا الصور واكتبوا الكلمة المناسبة
the images that you see.
للصور التي ترونها.
When you understand the images, you will be
عندما تفهمون الصور، ستتمكنون
able to play a communication game with your
من لعب لعبة تواصل مع زملائكم
classmates.
في الصف.
Let's do this activity together first.
دعونا نقوم بهذا النشاط معاً أولاً.
Okay, number one is clap, clap,
حسناً، رقم واحد هو clap, clap (يصفق - yuṣaffiqu),
like that.
هكذا.
Number two, number two is close,
رقم اثنين، رقم اثنين هو close (يغلق - yughliqu),
close, like that.
close, هكذا.
Number three, number three is drink, drink,
رقم ثلاثة، رقم ثلاثة هو drink (يشرب - yashrabu), drink,
drink, drink.
drink, drink.
Number four is eat,
رقم أربعة هو eat (يأكل - yaʾkulu),
eat, eat, eat.
eat, eat, eat.
Number five is jump, j-u-m-p.
رقم خمسة هو jump (يقفز - yaqfizu), j-u-m-p.
J-u-m-p, j-u-m-p.
J-u-m-p, j-u-m-p.
Number six is open, o-p, open,
رقم ستة هو open (يفتح - yaftaḥu), o-p, open,
open.
open.
Number seven, play, p-l-a-y.
رقم سبعة، play (يلعب - yalʿabu / يعزف - yaʿzifu), p-l-a-y.
Number eight, number eight is read, r-e
رقم ثمانية، رقم ثمانية هو read (يقرأ - yaqraʾu), r-e
-a-d, read.
-a-d, read.
Number nine, number nine is run, n
رقم تسعة، رقم تسعة هو run (يجري - yajrī), n
-r-u-n.
-r-u-n.
Number 10 is sit, s-i
رقم عشرة هو sit (يجلس - yajlisu), s-i
-t, not e, not seat, s-i-t,
-t, ليس e, ليس seat, s-i-t,
sit.
sit.
Number 11, 11 is stomp, s-t,
رقم أحد عشر، أحد عشر هو stomp (يدب بقدمه - yadubbu bi-qadamih), s-t,
stomp.
stomp.
Number 12 is walk, walk.
رقم اثنا عشر هو walk (يمشي - yamshī), walk.
This letter is silent, walk.
هذا الحرف لا يُنطق، walk.
Last one, number 13, 13, write, write.
الأخير، رقم ثلاثة عشر، ثلاثة عشر، write (يكتب - yaktubu), write.
This letter is silent, write.
هذا الحرف لا يُنطق، write.